Guide to the Interseminary Commission for Training for the Rural Ministry Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Interseminary Commission for Training for the Rural Ministry Records
1926-1954
RG 47
Yale University Divinity School Library
3
(6 boxes)
Minutes, reports and proposals document the development and activities of the Commission, including its participation in the Associated Commissions for the Development of the Rural Church in New England. Correspondence focuses on Luther A. Weigle's involvement in the Commission. The Interseminary Commission for Training for the Rural Ministry was established in 1929, with funding from John D. Rockefeller, Jr., as a cooperative effort to provide more adequate preparation for ministers working in town and country fields. The activities of the Interseminary Commission included summer institutes, research seminars, supervised fieldwork, and courses offered in connection with the seven participating seminaries: Andover Newton Theological School, Auburn Theological Seminary, Boston University School of Theology, Bangor Theological Seminary, Hartford Theological Seminary, Union Theological Seminary and Yale Divinity School.
Interseminary Commission for Training for the Rural Ministry
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
The Interseminary Commission for Training for the Rural Ministry was established in 1929 as a cooperative effort to provide more adequate preparation for ministers working in town and country fields. Participating seminaries were: the Andover Newton Theological School, Auburn Theological Seminary, Boston University School of Theology, Bangor Theological Seminary, Hartford Theological School, Union Theological Seminary and the Yale Divinity School. Dean Luther A. Weigle of the Yale Divinity School was chairman of the Commission for many years. The activities of the Interseminary Commission included summer institutes, research seminars, supervised fieldwork, and courses offered in connection with the seven schools involved. The initial funding for the Commission was received from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Later, the Commission was funded by the participating seminaries.
Scope and Contents
The first three series are arranged chronologically. The minutes, reports and proposals date from 1928 to 1950 and document the development and activities of the Commission including its participation in the Associated Commissions for the Development of the Rural Church in New England. The correspondence dates from 1926 to 1950 and centers around Luther A. Weigle's involvement in the Commission. Correspondence of the staff of the Commission is included as well as letters to and from the deans and presidents of the participating seminaries who served as the board of directors. Correspondence regarding funding, including letters to and from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his representatives, is filed with the financial material of Series III. Series III also includes financial statements, expense account reports and minutes of the Finance Committee.
The subject file of Series IV is divided into four sections:
A. Field work instruments; including questionnaires and interview guides, completed and blank. (1929-1945, nd)
B. Staff papers and memoranda (l930-1948, nd)
C. Student seminar reports and course descriptions (1928-195~)
D. Summer schools and conferences (1928-1948)
The material is arranged alphabetically by subject within each of these sections, except in the case of the student seminar reports, which are arranged chronologically.
One oversize photograph of the Interseminary Commission board and staff completes the record group.
Arrangement
I. Minutes, Reports, Proposals, 1928-1950, n.d.
II. Correspondence of Staff and Board Members, 1926-1950, n.d.
III. Financial Material, 1929-1950, n.d.
IV. Subject File, 1928-1954, n.d.
Religion -- Fieldwork; Religious education; Universities and colleges -- Religion; Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison), 1874-1960; Weigle, Luther A. (Luther Allan), 1880-1976; Andover Newton Theological School; Associated Commissions for the Development of the Rural Church in New England; Auburn Theological Seminary (Auburn, N.Y.); Bangor Theological Seminary (Me.); Boston University. School of Theology; Hartford Theological Seminary; Union Theological Seminary (New York, N.Y.); Yale University. Divinity School
- Minutes, Reports, Proposals, 1928-1950, n.d.; Series I
  - Interseminary Commission records, 1928-1949, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
- Correspondence of Staff and Board Members, 1926-1950, n.d; Series II
  - Correspondence, 1926-1933 Jul (Box 2, Folder 12-27)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Aug- 1950 (Box 3, Folder 28-48)
- Financial Material, 1929-1950, n.d; Series III
  - Financial records, 1929-1950, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 49-59)
- Subject File, 1928-1954, n.d.; Series IV
  - Questionnaires, interview guides: The Approach, the Method, and Especially the Content of Training for the Rural Ministry, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Questionnaires, interview guides: Household Study Survey, nd (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Questionnaires, interview guides: Rural Religious Education, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Questionnaires, interview guides: Rural-Urban Adjustments, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Questionnaires, interview guides: Rural-Urban Adjustments, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Questionnaires, interview guides: Miscellaneous, 1931-1945, nd (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Staff papers, memoranda: The Integration of Education for the Christian Ministry, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Staff papers, memoranda: Relation of Student Field Work to Theological Education, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Staff papers, memoranda: Miscellaneous, re. the rural church, 1930-1945, nd (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Student seminar reports, course descriptions: incl: The Church and Country Youth, 1928-1933 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Student seminar reports, course descriptions: incl: Seminary extension service for the untrained minister in the rural field, 1934-1936 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Student seminar reports, course descriptions: incl: Rural-urban adjustments, 1937-1942 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Student seminar reports, course descriptions: incl: Small sects in rural America, 1942-1946 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Student seminar reports,course descriptions: incl: methods of church cooperation, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Student seminar reports, course descriptions: incl: An adequate program for the town and country church, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Student seminar reports, course descriptions: incl: How does the church function in the local community?, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Student seminar reports, course descriptions: incl: The rural non-farm population; the rural mission of the World Church, 1950-1954, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Summer schools and conferences: Auburn and Bangor, 1930-1948 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Summer schools and:conferences: Boston University - Yale Divinity School, miscellaneous, 1928-1944 (Box 6, Folder 78)